When working with Excel, there
may be occasions where you
wish to automate a process.
So it's quite simply would assign a
shortcut key to allow you to assign a
feature or a function to allow you to
just press a shortcut key, and then
that will carry out that process.
There are a wide range of macros
available and you can do some research
on the internet and it is good to learn
some Visual Basic coding skills for
macros, but there is an awful lot of
macro out there that you can utilise
and apply into your spreadsheets
depending on what you wish to do.
And I have applied a link at the
bottom of the page, which you can
follow to give you some further
guidance and some tuition on this.
So just to demonstrate how you can
create a macro is in this spreadsheet
that we've be working on, I'm going
to create a macro, which will input
the average sales simply by adding
or clicking on the shortcut key.
And the first thing I need to
do is obviously I've deleted all
of the average sales data there.
What I need to do now is I
need to set up the macro.
So, the easiest way to do that is
if I just select the view tab and on
the view tab, if I look along to the
right I can see macro, and then I
click on that and select record macro.
Now it's got the name macro
seven, which I'm happy with.
I need to assign a shortcut key, which I
want to select L, so it's Control and L
will be the shortcut key to activate this.
And for description, I'm just going
to go average sales select OK.
Now macros is being recorded now.
So the macro is being recorded,
so I need to do something.
So if I go into that cell there, and
then I go to the home tab and I go to
the auto sum and select average, and
it gives me the average figure there.
So I can now go back to the view tab
on the macros and then stop recording.
So basically I've recorded the average
sales, adding the average sales to that
and now it's been assigned to a shortcut.
If I go to Control and L.
It will automatically add the average.
As you can see on the formula bar it's
coming up with subtotal, but that is still
the average function being applied there,
so if I go to the next one, it's just
displaying it in a slightly different
way, but it is still the average sales as
you can see, which is 25 and July sales.
So that's how you're going to sign a
macros just to quickly automate a process
so rather than having to continually go
to the home tab and select whichever tool
or function I wish to use, I can actually
assign that to a shortcut key, which would
then allow me to speed the process up.
You can also use macros in Word.
So again, you may want to have some
research on that and see if you can find
anything useful that will assist you.